<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: foil | Thinking Out Loud]]></title>
  <link href="http://ajdecon.github.com/blog/categories/foil/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ajdecon.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-04-12T13:23:58-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://ajdecon.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Adam DeConinck]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[ajdecon@ajdecon.org]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fencing tourney report: Friday Night Foil Fight 4/17 ]]></title>
    <link href="http://ajdecon.github.com/fencing-tourney-report-friday-night-foil-figh/"/>
    <updated>2009-04-18T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://ajdecon.github.com/fencing-tourney-report-friday-night-foil-figh</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><b>Net result: Pool record 3-2, seeded 6/12, lost first DE 11-15</b> <p />&nbsp;Despite the less-than-stellar showing in the end, this was probably my <br />best foil tournament to date. A large part of this was because last <br />night's foil fight was a bit smaller than average and involved mainly <br />locals--the sectionals in indianapolis leached away most of the area <br />fencers who might otherwise have shown. <p />&nbsp;Foil is also very much not my weapon of choice, with its focus on <br />right-of-way and parry-riposte sequences. My epee game lately has <br />focused much more on timing, point control and distance control, all <br />of which would have served me well in this tournament. Too bad I <br />didn't actually fence that way; but on the whole I feel really good <br />about how things went. <p />&nbsp;My pool went reasonably well, partly because of a larger-than-usual <br />concentration of beginners. My two losses were against G, a <br />left-hander from my club, and Blue. In both cases I lost because I <br />was too aggressive, charging in too quickly and not controlling <br />distance well. All of the things I had already corrected in epee, in <br />other words... I have to chalk that up to not taking foil as <br />seriously, but that's not something I should do again. <p />&nbsp;I started my first DE in the first way and got incredibly frustrated, <br />completely losing control of the bout. At the end of the first period <br />I was at 7-13 against, angry and hotheaded. The break really saved <br />me: I walked away, calmed down, tried to get back into a more <br />deliberate state of mind. And it helped a lot: the 2nd period was <br />much slower and I took four straight touches to his one, ending at <br />11-14. My opponent then took a final touch to win at the beginning of <br />the third period, but by the end he was obviously getting nervous <br />about the erosion of his lead. <p />&nbsp;What did I learn? I fence much better in a calm, deliberate and <br />less-energetic style than I do aggressively, which might explain why I <br />enjoy epee so much more than foil. Distance control saved my ass in <br />the 2nd period of my DE: a lot of my touches owed to being able to <br />keep my opponent out of range until I drew him in for a parry-riposte. <br />&nbsp;In general I also found that the high-out 6 guard I've been playing <br />with in epee helped a lot here, keeping my blade out of range of <br />beat-disengage attacks and helping my set the distance better. It <br />weakens my parry-4, and encourages a lot more parry-2 than I like, but <br />I got a fair number of parry 2-riposte to flank or back shots in that <br />are probably decent enough at my level. <p />&nbsp;Next up: Indianapolis tournament on May 2, probably foil and epee both.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
