<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: tournaments | Thinking Out Loud]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.ajdecon.org/blog/categories/tournaments/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.ajdecon.org/"/>
  <updated>2015-04-12T13:36:40-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.ajdecon.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Adam DeConinck]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[ajdecon@ajdecon.org]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fencing tourney report: Friday Night Foil Fight 4/17 ]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.ajdecon.org/fencing-tourney-report-friday-night-foil-figh/"/>
    <updated>2009-04-18T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.ajdecon.org/fencing-tourney-report-friday-night-foil-figh</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><b>Net result: Pool record 3-2, seeded 6/12, lost first DE 11-15</b> <p />&nbsp;Despite the less-than-stellar showing in the end, this was probably my <br />best foil tournament to date. A large part of this was because last <br />night's foil fight was a bit smaller than average and involved mainly <br />locals--the sectionals in indianapolis leached away most of the area <br />fencers who might otherwise have shown. <p />&nbsp;Foil is also very much not my weapon of choice, with its focus on <br />right-of-way and parry-riposte sequences. My epee game lately has <br />focused much more on timing, point control and distance control, all <br />of which would have served me well in this tournament. Too bad I <br />didn't actually fence that way; but on the whole I feel really good <br />about how things went. <p />&nbsp;My pool went reasonably well, partly because of a larger-than-usual <br />concentration of beginners. My two losses were against G, a <br />left-hander from my club, and Blue. In both cases I lost because I <br />was too aggressive, charging in too quickly and not controlling <br />distance well. All of the things I had already corrected in epee, in <br />other words... I have to chalk that up to not taking foil as <br />seriously, but that's not something I should do again. <p />&nbsp;I started my first DE in the first way and got incredibly frustrated, <br />completely losing control of the bout. At the end of the first period <br />I was at 7-13 against, angry and hotheaded. The break really saved <br />me: I walked away, calmed down, tried to get back into a more <br />deliberate state of mind. And it helped a lot: the 2nd period was <br />much slower and I took four straight touches to his one, ending at <br />11-14. My opponent then took a final touch to win at the beginning of <br />the third period, but by the end he was obviously getting nervous <br />about the erosion of his lead. <p />&nbsp;What did I learn? I fence much better in a calm, deliberate and <br />less-energetic style than I do aggressively, which might explain why I <br />enjoy epee so much more than foil. Distance control saved my ass in <br />the 2nd period of my DE: a lot of my touches owed to being able to <br />keep my opponent out of range until I drew him in for a parry-riposte. <br />&nbsp;In general I also found that the high-out 6 guard I've been playing <br />with in epee helped a lot here, keeping my blade out of range of <br />beat-disengage attacks and helping my set the distance better. It <br />weakens my parry-4, and encourages a lot more parry-2 than I like, but <br />I got a fair number of parry 2-riposte to flank or back shots in that <br />are probably decent enough at my level. <p />&nbsp;Next up: Indianapolis tournament on May 2, probably foil and epee both.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fencing tourney report: Point Dufour Epee Tournament ]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.ajdecon.org/fencing-tourney-report-point-dufour-epee-tour/"/>
    <updated>2009-04-05T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.ajdecon.org/fencing-tourney-report-point-dufour-epee-tour</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><b>Net result: Pool record 0-5, seeded 17/18, first DE 15-10, second <br />DE 7-15.</b> <p />&nbsp;Yesterday was the 2009 Dufour Epee Tournament at <a href="http://www.thepointfencingclub.com/">the Point</a>. The <br />tournament's named after Marie France Dufour, a Canadian olympian who <br />was one of the original coaches at the club, and is held every year in <br />her honor. She didn't make it down from Canada this year, but <br />apparently she's done so in past years. <p />&nbsp;At three months and counting since I had gotten back into fencing, I <br />was feeling pretty decent about this tournament. I had done better <br />than I had expected in the last epee tourney a month or so ago, ending <br />up seeded towards the middle and only losing 15-14 in my second DE to <br />someone I expected to grind me to dust. This time I expected to do a <br />bit better, at least in pools. <p />&nbsp;This, of course, did not happen. <p />&nbsp;I was in a much tougher pool than the previous tourney: three D/E <br />fencers, including my coach, and the other two U's being both <br />left-handed, which I still don't know how to deal with very well. I <br />lost all my bouts, but mostly by respectably small margins. I only <br />lost one bout 0-5, which was frankly disastrous in every way: I had <br />unexpected equipment problems with both my primary and backup blades, <br />resulting in a red card and a point down before the bout had even <br />started, and having to fence with an unfamiliar blade my coach had <br />provided. I was angry and frustrated before the bout even started, <br />and my opponent (the pool's D) took me down pretty easily. <p />&nbsp;So I was seeded 17/18, but came into a bit of luck in that my first <br />elimination bout was against seed 16. After a shaky start--the guy <br />had a really good guard against direct arm attacks, which is what I <br />like to use--I managed to take control and won 15-10, where most of <br />his touches took advantage of the fact that I'm still dropping and <br />exposing my upper arm too much. <p />&nbsp;I lost my second elimination bout, 7-15, to DP, another fencer from my <br />club. This felt rather less bad, DP being an extremely strong epeeist <br />and seed 1 in this tournament; in fact, this may have beem my best <br />result against him to date. I got in a couple of nice hand and wrist <br />touches, and finished feeling like I hadn't been completely shut out, <br />which was my main goal for that bout. I may ask DP to work with me on <br />a few things later, as some of his touches were not things I expected. <p />&nbsp;I finished the tournament frustrated, though, until my coach talked me <br />down. He told me I had improved since the last tourney--hard to <br />believe!--and had simply been up against a tougher field. I'm still <br />not sure how much I believe that in my back-brain, but it at least had <br />the effect of getting me to look at my <i>fencing</i> rather than my <br />results, and note exactly what I had to work on and what I did right. <p />&nbsp;D and M also arrived later to take over the club for the first <br />practice of the Parkland Fencing Club, a club they're starting at <br />their community college. I stuck around and helped out teaching the <br />complete newbies, as D and M are both yet to finish their beginners' <br />class but still hugely enthusiastic about fencing and making the PFC a <br />reality. This honestly helped me cheer up and relax for the rest of <br />the evening: working on fencing basics is always helpful, and D and M <br />are simply fun people to be around which also honestly helped. <p />&nbsp;Next two tournaments are the Friday Night Foil Fight on April 17 <br />(which should be fun even though I suck at foil) and a tourney in <br />Indianapolis on May 2 where I plan to fence epee, and maybe foil if I <br />feel like being ridiculous. I can spend the next few weeks working on <br />problems I noticed from this tourney, mainly involving distance <br />control and killing bad habits.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
