<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: fantasy | Thinking Out Loud]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.ajdecon.org/blog/categories/fantasy/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.ajdecon.org/"/>
  <updated>2015-04-12T13:56:28-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.ajdecon.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Adam DeConinck]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[ajdecon@ajdecon.org]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Turn Coat, Book 11 of the Dresden Files, by Jim Butcher ]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.ajdecon.org/turn-coat-book-11-of-the-dresden-files-jim-bu/"/>
    <updated>2009-04-18T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.ajdecon.org/turn-coat-book-11-of-the-dresden-files-jim-bu</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last week I got my copy of Turn Coat, book 11 of Jim Butcher's Dresden <br />Files series. For the uninitiated, the Dresden Files follows the <br />adventures of Harry Dresden, the only wizard in Chicago's Yellow <br />Pages. Starting out mostly as a PI with some magical abilities, in <br />recent books Harry's adventures have shaded into more standard <br />urban-fantasy stories of magic, mystery and conspiracy. Especially <br />conspiracy, as Harry and others have come to the conclusion that there <br />must be a traitor in the ranks of the White Council, the governing <br />body of wizardry in this world. <br />&nbsp;<br />The book opens immediately with Harry answering his front door to find <br />Morgan, a long-time antagonist and Warden of the White Council who <br />thinks of Harry as a dangerous threat, asking for sanctuary from the <br />Council himself on a charge of murder. Harry, being a glutton for <br />punishment, of course allows him inside and decides that Morgan is <br />innocent. This sets off a chain of chaotic events in which everyone <br />is looking for Morgan, Harry is attempting to prove his innocence and <br />the involvement of the real traitor, and various friends and denizens <br />of Chicago are caught in the middle. <br />&nbsp;<br />Without giving away too many details, it's debatable whether the end <br />of this novel can really be called a victory. Harry technically <br />"wins" as usual, but he loses a lot in the process, and damages a <br />number of relationships and alliances along the way. He doesn't seem <br />to have gained much in the process, unlike previous books where he has <br />met new allies or gained new knowledge. <br />&nbsp;<br />Jim Butcher has talked about how the Dresden files will be a long <br />series with an "apocalyptic trilogy" at the end, and it's apparent <br />that this might be the turning point at which things start to get a <br />lot darker.  As a story I felt this was a stronger installment than <br />the last novel, "Small Favor", which didn't feel as tight or focused <br />to me as this latest one. At the same time I'm not sure how much I'm <br />looking forward to the next Dresden Files novel: this series has <br />always had its fair share of darkness but were lightened by Harry's <br />humor and relationships with his friends. As things get darker in <br />this world and alliances become strained, it's hard to see how much <br />light will be present as the series goes on... which may forward the <br />plot, but also lose a large part of why the series was so enjoyable in <br />the first place.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
