<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: scifi | Thinking Out Loud]]></title>
  <link href="http://ajdecon.github.com/blog/categories/scifi/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ajdecon.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-04-12T13:31:50-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://ajdecon.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Adam DeConinck]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[ajdecon@ajdecon.org]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book Review: YOU]]></title>
    <link href="http://ajdecon.github.com/book-review-you/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-27T12:56:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://ajdecon.github.com/book-review-you</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/15790854-you">YOU</a>, by Austin Grossman,
is a novel about video games, growing up with your high school friends,
and figuring out what the hell you
really want to do with the rest of your life.</p>

<p>Our lead character is Russell, a 28-year-old English major who has wandered
through several possible careers with no particular attachment or aptitude for
any of them, and at the beginning of the novel he is interviewing with a video
game studio. Black Arts, the studio in question, was founded by a
couple of his friends from high school; but while Russell was peripherally
involved in building the first version of the studio's game engine
(as part of a group project back in school), he hasn't been involved for a long
time and barely squeaks in as an entry-level designer.</p>

<p>All of Black Arts games follow the same four characters, a pretty standard
four-person D&amp;D-style adventuring party including a warrior named Brennan,
a thief named Prendar, a wizard named Lorac,
and a female warrior named Leira. Starting with
a high fantasy series called <em>Realms of Gold</em>, these four characters are
then re-purposed and
re-used for anything from espionage to science fiction to golf
and go-cart games.</p>

<p>The adventuring party roughly mirrors the original
four-person group that built the game back in high school: Simon, the
enigmatic genius (and wizard), now deceased; Darren, Simon's partner in
co-founding Black Arts (and warrior); Lisa, a brilliant programmer in her own
right, but disconnected from the world (similar to Leira);
and Russell, who seems to me less a thief than someone who just doesn't know
what do do with his life.</p>

<p>While the novel follows Russell and the Black Arts team through the development
of the next installment in their <em>Realms of Gold</em> series, and through
various adventures in the realm of making video games, this really is
the story of those four characters: a group of misfits who banded together in
high school, then found their own paths after graduation after they
discovered they were going to be stuck living in the real world after all.
The story makes frequent use of flashbacks to high school, a computer summer
camp, college, and other moments which help us learn about how these four
grew up together and then grew apart.</p>

<p>I enjoyed this novel immensely (and finished it within 24 hours of purchasing
it!),
but it had its ups and downs. Much of the story felt a little "dream-like":
large parts of the novel either consisted of flashbacks to Russel's past,
imagined flashbacks about what Simon or Lisa might have been feeling at the
same time, or conversations between Russell and the actual adventurers from
the Black Arts games.</p>

<p>In a way, this worked -- a lot of the story
took place hacking on games at two in the morning, and I know from personal
experience that things do feel a little dream-like during those moments -- but
it made up so much of the novel that it lost a bit of its immediacy. Perhaps
because of this, Russell felt so detached from the outcome of his company's
struggles that it became hard to care much as the reader.</p>

<p>However, all that is really a minor quibble.
The story of Black Arts was a lot of fun to read,
and offers much to the reader who knows
games. It's set in the late 90's, a pretty good time for video games in my
opinion, and there are all sorts of great nostalgia references for anyone who
grew up playing video games around that time. I also enjoy Grossman's writing
style quite a lot, both here and in his superhero novel <em>Soon I Will Be
Invincible</em>.</p>

<p>Call it 8/10.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Where do we come from? The dark side of the moon!]]></title>
    <link href="http://ajdecon.github.com/where-do-we-come-from-the-dark-side-of-the-moon-a-review-of-iron-sky/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-29T05:20:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://ajdecon.github.com/where-do-we-come-from-the-dark-side-of-the-moon-a-review-of-iron-sky</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Months ago I came across a movie trailer which I had to share with everyone I knew.
I was convinced that this movie could be nothing but concentrated awesome. It
looked like it had everything an excellent action movie needs...
witty dialogue, funny moments, space battles, huge explosions,
and of course... Nazis.</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/Py_IndUbcxc" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>




<!-- more -->


<p>Unfortunately, <a href="http://www.ironsky.net/">Iron Sky</a> was one of those movies that couldn't quite live up
to its own trailer. I still quite enjoyed it, but it definitely falls into the "indie cult B-movie"
category, and it isn't a particularly re-watchable example of the genre.</p>

<p>To recap the concept briefly: In 1945, to escape their defeat, the Nazi Party of Germany established
a moon base where they would regroup and eventually retake the Earth. In 2018, a returning American
mission to the Moon, under the presidency of someone who looks suspiciously like Sarah Palin,
discovers the Nazi base. A captured American astronaut, a recon mission to Earth, and an eventual
all-out space war follow, with all sorts of hilarity and fun action sequences.</p>

<p>I love the concept, as silly movies go; and since the filmmakers are primarily Finnish,
it escapes being a simple "America wins!" movie. But the writing was honestly just... not great.
A few of the performances were enjoyable, including <a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm1087430/">Julia Dietze</a>
as Renate Richter, but most of them were mediocre and forgettable.</p>

<p>I will say, however, that the production value was amazing. The space sequences looked as good
as most recent blockbuster science fiction movies, the world was well-imagined, and there were
so many awesome little details. I am not the sort of person to gush about costuming in a movie,
but I thought just about everything in the Nazi moon base looked perfect. Whoever the
production designers were for this movie obviously had a lot of fun, and did an amazing job.
It's only the writers and the actors who disappointed me. :-)</p>

<p>Verdict? Definitely worth watching, but only once. Rent it from Amazon, don't buy it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Whedon on Romney: A candidate who isn't afraid to bring about the zombie apocalypse]]></title>
    <link href="http://ajdecon.github.com/whedon-on-romney-a-candidate-who-isnt-afraid-to-bring-about-the-zombie-apocalypse/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-29T05:08:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://ajdecon.github.com/whedon-on-romney-a-candidate-who-isnt-afraid-to-bring-about-the-zombie-apocalypse</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<iframe width="560" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/6TiXUF9xbTo" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>I typically try to keep this blog a politics-free zone, as I think MPI, Fortran, science fiction, and zombies are all
much more interesting topics to talk about.</p>

<p>Thankfully, we've got some zombies right here for you...</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
